>> Stephen: WELCOME BACK,
EVERYBODY, TO "THE LATE SHOW,"
ALREADY IN PROGRESS.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN, YOU KNOW
MY FIRST GUEST FROM MOVIES SUCH
AS "SPEED," "POINT BREAK", "THE
MATRIX," AND THE "JOHN WICK"
SERIES OF INSTRUCTIONAL VIDEOS.
PLEASE WELCOME, KEANU REEVES!
( CHEERS AND APPLAUSE )
♪ ♪ ♪
>> STEPHEN!
( CHEERS )
>> Stephen: GOOD TO SEE YOU
AGAIN.
HOW HAVE YOU BEEN?
>> I'VE BEEN GOOD.
( CHEERS )
YEAH, GOOD EVENING.
>> Stephen: PEOPLE ENJOY--
PEOPLE ENJOY THE KEANU REEVES.
THAT'S VERY NICE.
>> THAT IS NICE!
THANK YOU.
>> Stephen: THE LATEST
INSTALLMENT OF "JOHN WICK" SHOWS
YOU WITH REALLY EXTRAORDINARY
AGILITY.
AND-- AND PHYSICAL CAPABILITY.
YOU-- YOU-- YOU SAY YOU DON'T DO
YOUR STUNTS, BUT DO YOU YOUR
ACTION.
>> I DO ACTION, YEAH.
>> Stephen: WHAT DOES THAT
MEAN "DO YOUR ACTION" AS OPPOSED
TO YOUR STUNT?
>> OKAY SO I'LL DO SOME FIGHT
SCENES, AND THEN JOHN WICK WILL
GET HIT BY A CAR, AND THAT'S
JACKSON SPIDEL--
>> Stephen: THAT'S YOUR STUNT
MAN.
>> YES, WHO IS AN AMAZING STUNT
AND HE GETS HIT BY THE CAR.
THEN I'LL GET UP FROM THE CAR,
AND THEN I'LL DO A WHOLE BUNCH
MORE OF, LIKE, ARE KUNG FU AND
WHATEVER AND JUDO.
AND THEN MAYBE, YOU KNOW, THEN
IF I GET THROWN OFF OF
SOMETHING, THEN JACKSON DOES HIS
THING.
>> Stephen: RIGHT.
>> BUT IN THE FILM --
>> Stephen: BUT YOU COULD IF
YOU WANTED TO, BUT YOU DON'T
WANT TO TAKE HIS JOB AWAY.
>> I COULD GET HIT BY A CAR BUT,
YOU KNOW, HOSPITAL.
( LAUGHTER ).
>> Stephen: OH, YOU COULD GET
HIT BY A CAR ONCE, LAST FILM.
>> THAT'S IT.
>> Stephen: YES.
>> BUT JACKSON IS A
PROFESSIONAL, AND HE KNOWS HOW
TO DO THAT AND-- BUT, I MEAN,
FOR JOHN WICK ACTION IS A
PARTICULAR KIND OF ACTION.
THE DIRECTOR WANTS TO MAKE IT
IMMERSIVE AND WANTS TO MAKE IT
LUKE A PERFORMANCE, SO IT'S
REALLY LONG TAKES.
SO WE-- YOU KNOW, YOU TRAIN FOR
A WHILE.
>> Stephen: WHAT I LOVE IS YOU
SEE THE FIGHT HAPPENING.
>> YEAH, EXACTLY.
>> Stephen: IT'S LIKE WATCHING
DANCE.
>> YEAH, IT'S VERY MUCH LIKE
THAT.
THE DIRECTOR HAS A VISION, THEN
THERE'S SOME CHOREOGRAPHY MOST
OF THE TIME.
AND THEN-- AND THEN WE GO, WE
REHEARSE AND THEN WE PERFORM.
>> Stephen: A SINGLE FIGHT,
LET'S SAY ONE FIVE-MINUTE FIGHT,
YOU MIGHT DO, HOW LONG ARE YOU
TRAINING FOR THAT FIGHT?
>> WELL, IT DEPENDS.
SO THEY DON'T-- OKAY SO, THERE'S
A COUPLE FIGHTS WHERE WE TRAINED
A COUPLE OF DAYS, BUT WHAT
REALLY HAPPENS IS FOR ME, THEY
GET-- I GET BASICALLY LIKE A
JOHN WICK TOOLBOX SO I'LL KNOW
HOWEVER MANY JUDO THROWS.
THEY'LL CHOREOGRAPH MOST OF THE
JUJITSU.
WITH THE HORSE, THERE'S A HORSE
FIGHT NOW.
SO I HAVE TO DO SOME --
>> Stephen: YOU FIGHT A HORSE.
>> I HAD TO GET OFF THE SADDLE.
NO, I'M ON THE HORSE AND THEN --
>> Stephen: THE HORSE IS
FIGHTING.
THE HORSE IS FIGHTING.
>> IT'S JOHN WICK.
IT'S LIKE, INSTEAD OF JUST
RIDING THE HORSE YOU HAVE TO
HAVE A GUN FIGHT AND DO ALL OF
THAT SORT OF STUFF.
>> Stephen: WHAT IS IT LIKE TO
FIGHT ON A HORSE?
>> IT'S FUN.
( LAUGHTER ).
>> Stephen: DOES THAT MAKE YOU
NERVOUS AT ALL?
>> NO!
IT'S A MOVIE!
IT'S FUN!
>> Stephen: BUT THE HORSE IS
REAL.
YOU COULD GETUE COULD GET THROWN
AND TRAMPLED.
>> YEAH, YOU CAN DIE.
( LAUGHTER )
BUT THE THING IS-- BUT THE THING
IS, I MEAN --
>> Stephen: I WASN'T GOING TO
GO THAT FAR, BUT THAT'S TRUE.
>> THAT'S WHAT CAN HAPPEN.
BUT THEY HAVE A SAFETY SYSTEM SO
THEY CREATED THIS RIG, WITH THE
HORSE BEHIND A TRUCK AND THE
THING --
>> Stephen: THEY STRAP THE
HORSE BEHIND A TRUCK.
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
>> WELL KIND-- IT'S VERY
COMPLICATED.
BUT ANYWAY, YOU WON'T SEE THAT
IN THE MOVIE.
I'LL JUST BE RIDING, AND IT WILL
LOOK-- HOPEFULLY PEOPLE WILL
ENJOY IT, BUT--
( APPLAUSE )
( CHEERS )
BUT IT'S JOHN WICK!
>> Stephen: I THINK WE HAVE--
I THINK WE HAVE AN IMAGE-- I
THINK WE HAVE AN IMAGE.
IS THIS THE HORSE THING?
>> YEAH, YEAH, BUT THAT'S
ACTUALLY JUST RIDING.
>> Stephen:  THAT'S JUST
RIDING, OKAY.
>> THAT'S JUST RIDING.
THERE'S A WHOLE OTHER THING THAT
HAPPENS.
>> Stephen: DID YOU KNOW HOW
TO RIDE BEFORE THIS?
>> YEAH, A LITTLE BIT.
A LITTLE BIT.
>> Stephen: HAVE YOU EVER
PLAYED A COWBOY?
>> NO.
>> Stephen: OKAY.
>> YEAH.
I'D LIKE TO.
A WESTERN WOULD BE FUN.
>> Stephen: SURE.
>> BUT WITH THIS IT WAS JUST--
YOU KNOW, I WORKED WITH A
SECOND-GENERATION HORSE MASTER
TAD GRIFFITH AND HIS FAMILY.
YEAH, I MEAN, THAT'S REALLY WHAT
HAPPENS A LOT WITH JOHN WICK IS
YOU GET TO MEET THESE GREAT
INSTRUCTORS AND TEACHERS.
HEAL BERRY WORKED ON THE FILM.
SHE WAS GREAT, AND SHE WENT INTO
JOHN WICK ACTION.
SHE WORKED WITH TWO BELGIAN
DOGS.
HER CHARACTER HAS DOGS.
AND SHE TRAINED WITH THEM FOR
OVER --
>> Stephen: THAT'S THIS.
>> THAT'S THE SHOT.
SHE HAD TO DO SOME JOHN WICK
ACTION.
WHICH THEN SHE TRAINED FOR
ABOUT-- OVER SIX MONTHS.
>> Stephen: SO YOU'RE WORKING
WITH HORSES.
YOU'RE WORKING WITH DOGS.
IS IT HARD TO WORK WITH THE
ANIMALS ON SET?
>> NO, AS LONG AS YOU BUILD,
"LIKE A RELATIONSHIP WITH THEM.
>> Stephen: WHAT WAS YOUR
RELATIONSHIP TO THESE DOGS?
(  LAUGHTER  ).
>> I DIDN'T DO THE HALLE BERRY
SIX-MONTH TRAINING BECAUSE THEY
WERE HER DOGS.
OKAY, AN EXAMPLE WOULD BE THE
FIRST DAY THAT I WENT TO TRAIN
WITH HEAL WHO HAD BEEN TRAINING
WITH WONDERFUL DOGS, THE TRAINER
SAID, "SO HALLEY'S GOING TO
STAND THERE.
THERE SHE IS AND THERE ARE HER
TWO DOGS.
YOU'RE GOING TO WALK UP TO THEM.
DON'T LOOK AT THEM.
DON'T LOOK AT THEM IN THE EYE."
>> Stephen: WHY.
>> BECAUSE THEY'LL-- THEY-- THEY
MIGHT DO SOMETHING NOT GOOD.
NOW, THESE ANIMALS ARE REALLY
BEAUTIFUL AND FRIENDLY AND
AWESOME --
>> Stephen: AS LONG AS YOU
DON'T LOOK AT THEM.
( LAUGHTER )
THAT SOUNDS REALLY DANGEROUS.
DID YOU GO, "YOU KNOW, NO MORE
'JOHN WICK' MOVIES IF THAT DOG
TAKES MY FACE OFF."
>> NO, YOU JUST HAVE TO PAY
ATTENTION.
AND EVENTUALLY I GOT TO KNOW
THEM BETTER AND HE STILL TOLD ME
NOT TO LOOK AT THEM.
HALE WORKED SO MUCH THE TRAINER
TOLD ME-- HALE BY THE END WAS
HELLO.
AND GIVING COMMANDS.
AND IF YOU SEE THE FILM, IT'S
PRETTY SPECTACULAR WHAT THEY DO
TOGETHER.
>> Stephen: DID THE HORSE EVER
GET SPOOKED BY THE DOGS OR, LIKE
--
>> NO, THEY NEVER MET EACH
OTHER.
>> Stephen: OKAY.
>> NO.
BUT DOG THEY HAD IN "JOHN WICK"
ESCAPED ONCE IN TIMES SQUARE AT
5:00 IN THE MORNING ASK WENT
AFTER ONE THOSE OF HORSES WITH
THE CARTS.
>> Stephen: THE FIRST DOG--
>> I MEAN, IT DIDN'T GO AFTER
IT.
WE WERE DOING A SCENE, AND THEN
THE HORSE AND THE THING, AND THE
DOG WENT, "OH!"
AND IT DID A DOG THING.
IT WENT AFTER THE-- OH, YEAH,
AND THEN THERE WAS-- WHEN WE
WERE IN MOROK OH, YEAH, THERE
WERE THE DOGS AND A LOT OF CATS.
SO WE HAD, LIKE, CAT CHAOS.
>> Stephen: ARE THESE TRAINED
CATS OR WILD CATS?
>> THESE ARE WILD CATS WITH THE
DOGS.
SO THEN WE WOULD BE DOING A
SCENE AND, "CAT!
CAT!
CAT!"
AND THE DOGS WERE JUST LIKE BUT
THE THING IS WITH THE DOGS, YOU
CAN'T JUST GRAB THE DOG BECAUSE
IF YOU --
>> Stephen: RIGHT, BECAUSE...
EXACTLY.
YOU MIGHT ACTUALLY MAKE EYE
CONTACT.
YES, UH-HUH.
>> EXCITING TIMES.
>> Stephen: YEAH.
WE HAVE A CLIP HERE.
THIS IS NOT THE HORSE?
WHAT IS THIS?
THIS IS THE MOTORCYCLE.
>> YES.
>> Stephen: THIS IS THE
MOTORCYCLE.
WHAT'S GOG HERE?
>> WE WANTED TO OPEN UP THE JOHN
WICK ACTION IN THE FILM.
WE HAD SOME HORSES AND SOME
DOGS.
AND NOW THE DIRECTOR HAD THE
IDEA OF NINJAS AND A MOTORCYCLE
FIGHT.
>> Stephen: SURE, OBVIOUSLY,
THAT'S A NATURAL.
>> IT'S JOHN WICK, BABY!
>> Stephen: COME ON.
JIM.
WICK IT.
( CHEERS AND APPLAUSE )
>> IT'S FUN.
IT'S FUN!
>> Stephen: WELL, YOUR FANS
ARE PRETTY DARN EXCITED ABOUT A
RECENT ANNOUNCEMENT.
YOU'RE REPRIZING ANOTHER CLASSIC
ROLE FROM YOUR PAST.
YOU AND YOUR FRIEND ALEX WINTER
ANNOUNCED THAT--
( CHEERS AND APPLAUSE )
BILL AND TED ARE COMING BACK.
ANYTHING WE CAN KNOW ABOUT--
WHAT ARE THEY-- WHAT ARE THEY
DEALING WITH IN THIS ONE?
YOU CAN TELL ME ANYTHING ABOUT
IT.
>> SURE, RIGHT NOW IT'S CALLED
"BILL AND TED FACE THE MUSIC."
AND WE'RE FINDING THEM HOWEVER
MANY YEARS LATER-- I THINK IT'S
OVER 25.
AND THEY WERE SUPPOSED TO WRITE
THE SONG THAT WAS SUPPOSED TO
UNITE THE WORLD AND BRING PEACE
AND EVERYTHING, BUT THEY
HAVEN'T.
AND SO WHAT HAS THAT DONE TO
THEM?
>> Stephen: A LOT OF PRESSURE.
>> IT'S A --
>> Stephen: LOT OF PRESSURE.
>> PRESSURE.
AND YOU'VE GOT YOUR FAMILY NOW,
BUT YOU'RE STILL TRYING TO WRITE
THE SONG BECAUSE YOU HAVE TO
SAVE THE WORLD!
BUT THEN THE FUTURE COMES DOWN
AND SAYS, "WELL, NO, YOU DON'T
REALLY JUST HAVE TO SAVE THE
WORLD.
YOU HAVE TO SAEFORT UNIVERSE,
AND YOU HAVE TO WRITE THE SONG
IN, LIKE, 80 MINUTES."
>> Stephen: WOW.
>> THIES PROBLEM BECAUSE WE
HAVEN'T WRITTEN A SONG IN OVER
25 YEARS, SO WHAT ARE WE GOING
TO DO?
>> Stephen: WHAT HAPPENS TO
YOU IF YOU DON'T THIS DO THIS?
>> IT'S THE END OF THE UNIVERSE
AND TIME AND SPACE.
>> Stephen: YOU'RE FACING YOUR
MORTALITY AND ALL OF EXISTENCE?
>> YEAH.
>> Stephen: WOW.
WHAT DO YOU THINK HAPPENS WHEN
WE DIE, KEANU REEVES?
(  LAUGHTER  )
>> I KNOW THAT THE ONES WHO LOVE
US WILL MISS US.
>> Audience: OOOH!
( APPLAUSE )
>> Stephen: "JOHN WICK: CHAPTER
3-PARABELLUM" IS IN THEATERS
NEXT FRIDAY.
KEANU REEVES, EVERYBODY!
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK WITH
"TOOTSIE" STAR SANTINO FONTANA.